<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-08-24T21:07:46+10:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">DevScraps</title><subtitle>I spend most of my time performing the act of software creation and destruction, this place is about that, and whatever else I hit my head up against.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">DevScraps It’s just a Name</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blogging/2019/11/19/It's-just-a-name.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="DevScraps It’s just a Name" /><published>2019-11-19T17:46:23+10:00</published><updated>2019-11-19T17:46:23+10:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blogging/2019/11/19/It's-just-a-name</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blogging/2019/11/19/It's-just-a-name.html">&lt;p&gt;The original idea of the name of this blog was just so that I could move on and just write.  Yay, it’s doing just that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I write enough scraps, perhaps out of the great pile will emerge… ah you get the point.  Essentially, it’ll be good for something to commit to, provide more concrete learnings, track what I’ve done and generally something I could look back on and think, wow what was I thinking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another reason is that it is so close to being DevOps, but not.  So it’s already on trend.  If I followed this naming convention any closer it could have been DevBlogs, but there was no way I was going to have Blog in the title of a Blog.  DevWrites, DevPosts hmm… almost as &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.devsecopsdays.com/articles/its-just-a-name&quot; title=&quot;How did DevOps arise?&quot;&gt;bad as DevOps&lt;/a&gt;. As Devops borrows Developer oriented concepts to approach Operational concerns, I wanted DevScraps to be a Developers approach to just get me writing.  So lower the expectations to the writing and you have scraps.  All of this is of course entirely an afterthought, and I probably had been reading up on DevOps too much at the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, I apologize if this does all look like a pile of scrap.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Blogging" /><summary type="html">The original idea of the name of this blog was just so that I could move on and just write. Yay, it’s doing just that.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Prepping My Mac Part One(Actually, I just wanted Sidecar)</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blogging/2019/11/19/Prepping-My-Mac-Part-One-(Actually-I-just-wanted-Sidecar).html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Prepping My Mac Part One(Actually, I just wanted Sidecar)" /><published>2019-11-19T17:46:23+10:00</published><updated>2019-11-19T17:46:23+10:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blogging/2019/11/19/Prepping-My-Mac-Part-One-(Actually-I-just-wanted-Sidecar)</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blogging/2019/11/19/Prepping-My-Mac-Part-One-(Actually-I-just-wanted-Sidecar).html">&lt;p&gt;Coming back to development after some time traveling.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:travel&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:travel&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; I was optimistic and re-energized to get my Mac back in order.  First thing on my list was the delightful update of macOS from Mojave to Catalina&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:sarcastic&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:sarcastic&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.  On the feature aspect of macOS Catalina, focus was spent on refining their entertainment streaming options, a continued push for a more secure system, and a much appreciated device sync relocation.  To continue, the foundational Apps Notes and Remember have now matured and almost appear like options you’d pay for on the App store, but you’re getting for free.  Additionally you now get a wellness App, Screen-Time.  I like my time away from phones so hadn’t really noticed it on my phone, but seeing hours spent on the Mac may just nudge me in a healthier direction.  So of the new features, I was particularly interested in Sidecar which would turn your IPad into a second monitor.  Being away for quite a few months I was keen to get my system in order and apply this great free feature.  It took a bit more time than I would have liked, so I thought it would be worthwhile just writing about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the time macOS Catalina was still in Pre-Releasse, coincidentally for me I could take a bit of a risk as my Mac wasn’t in use for any critical work.  So I went gung-ho and installed it.  After the install, my network interface a &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.dlink.com/ProductInfo.aspx?m=DWA-182&quot; title=&quot;DWA 182&quot;&gt;D-Link DWA 182 dongle&lt;/a&gt; stopped working.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:network&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:network&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;  I attempted using the device drivers from the provider but they weren’t much help.  The latest drivers were missing the install file, and the previous driver didn’t work.  I gave up, reverted the system, and waited for the actual release to arrive&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:dongle&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:dongle&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.  It’s great how easy it is to waste time when you have it.  As I had only recently purchased my first IPad, I was eyeing the Sidecar feature. System requirements at the time allowed for my 2014 Macbook Pro to sneak in, however come release attempts to execute the Sidecar application proved futile as a dialog box indicated the feature was yet to be available at this time.  Later checking Apple’s website, the requirements list had been reduced to more modern superior Macs dating years from 2016 and onwards.  I don’t anticipate my lucking out changing either,  perhaps it had something to do with Apple’s Partners in the App store &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.astropad.com/sherlocked-by-apple/&quot; title=&quot;Astropad begin sherlocked&quot;&gt;almost destroying their future&lt;/a&gt;.  Either way, I just couldn’t be left out, so I purchased a basic alternative, the Duet App.  The intention was to use it as an extra display while developing.  It turns out that it’s resolution and speed is good enough, the included touch bar is something I don’t have much experience with but yet to find it useful on the self standing second display.  After all the anticipation I had endured waiting for extra screen real-estate there is one great pity.  In time the dual monitor will be useful for developing in absence of a larger screen but until then I’ll be using my noise-cancelling headphones while linked to the IPad as I just can’t stand fan noise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I previously mentioned and probably well known at this stage, this Mac OS update wasn’t exactly a smooth ride for many.  For me the only real issue was that XCode ended up having to be removed and then reinstalled for the XCode CLI tools to work, a prerequisite on a Mac for most kind of development work.  In the next post I continue my renewed setup for development on a Mac for 2019.  I shall mention my further little battle’s installing ruby, ensuring it’s using OpenSSL not Apple’s own TLS and Crypto library, a slight speed bump with Homebrew and playful antics with rbenv setup in Emacs.  Or perhaps I won’t mention that last part, as with anything in Emacs configuration, it’s your own undoing&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:emacs&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:emacs&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:travel&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;I’d like to write about this when I can, I mean who doesn’t like talking about their travel experiences. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:travel&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:sarcastic&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Sightly sarcastic as I hear a few people had a rough time with the new OS. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:sarcastic&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:network&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;My Mac’s internal Network Card is deceased &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:network&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:dongle&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Oh yeh, my D-Link DWA 182 network adapter still required those extra drivers for the macOS Catalina.  Again, the manufacturers drivers were pointless, so this time resorted to available drivers from &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/chris1111/Wireless-USB-Adapter/blob/master/README.md&quot; title=&quot;Mac Wireless Drivers on Github&quot;&gt;community tested drivers&lt;/a&gt;.  These could have worked on the Pre-Release, but I wasn’t prepared to venture outside the manufacturer’s drivers, as well as the fact the Sidecar feature I was hoping for hadn’t landed in the macOS Pre-Release either. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:dongle&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:emacs&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;There is a lot of help out there, but be vigilant with your time. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:emacs&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Blogging" /><summary type="html">Coming back to development after some time traveling.1 I was optimistic and re-energized to get my Mac back in order. First thing on my list was the delightful update of macOS from Mojave to Catalina2. On the feature aspect of macOS Catalina, focus was spent on refining their entertainment streaming options, a continued push for a more secure system, and a much appreciated device sync relocation. To continue, the foundational Apps Notes and Remember have now matured and almost appear like options you’d pay for on the App store, but you’re getting for free. Additionally you now get a wellness App, Screen-Time. I like my time away from phones so hadn’t really noticed it on my phone, but seeing hours spent on the Mac may just nudge me in a healthier direction. So of the new features, I was particularly interested in Sidecar which would turn your IPad into a second monitor. Being away for quite a few months I was keen to get my system in order and apply this great free feature. It took a bit more time than I would have liked, so I thought it would be worthwhile just writing about it. I’d like to write about this when I can, I mean who doesn’t like talking about their travel experiences. &amp;#8617; Sightly sarcastic as I hear a few people had a rough time with the new OS. &amp;#8617;</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">My Just Write a First Post Post</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blogging/2019/05/04/my-just-write-a-first-post-post.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My Just Write a First Post Post" /><published>2019-05-04T18:46:23+10:00</published><updated>2019-05-04T18:46:23+10:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blogging/2019/05/04/my-just-write-a-first-post-post</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blogging/2019/05/04/my-just-write-a-first-post-post.html">&lt;p&gt;Being a programmer and generally someone who spends a great
deal of their time on the web, blogs have been an ideal source of interest 
and knowledge.  Like many others in my industry, I’ve been wanting to say I have a blog for.. alwhile.
I could go back as far as school days dabbling in HTML and CSS usually lent itself
to creating a blog site of some kind.  I would try different hosts 
beginning with Geocities, then Angelfire and find myself looking further into 
Client/Server Architecture with the inevitable Wordpress.  Initially I wanted to 
blog, but the real attraction was to delve into the
technologies.  As a result, no blog made it any further than a couple 
initial statements about my fancy new blog.  Decades later many kinds of 
newfangled ways to make your own blog has arisen to make it even easier and I still don’t have a 
blog I can present.  Here is another attempt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This time I have cleared all of my reminders and scheduled tasks to ‘Begin the blog’, 
or ‘write post on..’, and didn’t allow myself to fork my attention to 
deciding blogging frameworks, or how I could easily publish from Emacs Org Mode, 
or which languages I could build and future rewrite a blogging application in. 
Yes, this was my spare time we’re talking about, and when considering a blog
the implementation details always seemed to nudge ahead, in my time I could play around if I wanted to.
  This always lead to not having a blog of course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where to from here? A bit like going to the gym I’m just getting on with it. I’m picking up from my last
attempt using Github Pages which had been sitting idle for 5 years,
without a post that I allowed to remain. I have a mounting pile of posts to write and complete.
It has become a habit to 
take chunks of daily notes of ideas and thoughts, with the intention that some day the bits
will form a helpful passage in a blog, 
the only thing was that they didn’t budge from their scribbly note form into a blog all by themselves. 
Many of my initial posts will be picked off the pile as I see fit, touched up into 
that something that makes sense to others, and posted with a gentle sigh of relief.
This will mean a number of different type of posts being published some short, some
long, some introspective, surely some technical and hopefully helpful,
some perhaps a bit of a ramble but I’ll be happy about the process of learning
through writing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you kindly for your interest in reading thus far, hopefully you find 
it beneficial and please reach out to me if you have would like to
say something nice or to find out more.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Blogging" /><summary type="html">Being a programmer and generally someone who spends a great deal of their time on the web, blogs have been an ideal source of interest and knowledge. Like many others in my industry, I’ve been wanting to say I have a blog for.. alwhile. I could go back as far as school days dabbling in HTML and CSS usually lent itself to creating a blog site of some kind. I would try different hosts beginning with Geocities, then Angelfire and find myself looking further into Client/Server Architecture with the inevitable Wordpress. Initially I wanted to blog, but the real attraction was to delve into the technologies. As a result, no blog made it any further than a couple initial statements about my fancy new blog. Decades later many kinds of newfangled ways to make your own blog has arisen to make it even easier and I still don’t have a blog I can present. Here is another attempt.</summary></entry></feed>