<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-11-13T09:34:58+07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Dev Scraps</title><subtitle>I spend most of my time performing the act of software creation and destruction, this place is about that, and whatever else I hit my head up against.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Welcome to Jekyll!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2019/11/12/welcome-to-jekyll.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome to Jekyll!" /><published>2019-11-12T18:04:32+07:00</published><updated>2019-11-12T18:04:32+07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2019/11/12/welcome-to-jekyll</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2019/11/12/welcome-to-jekyll.html">&lt;p&gt;You’ll find this post in your &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory. Go ahead and edit it and re-build the site to see your changes. You can rebuild the site in many different ways, but the most common way is to run &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;jekyll serve&lt;/code&gt;, which launches a web server and auto-regenerates your site when a file is updated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll requires blog post files to be named according to the following format:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;YEAR-MONTH-DAY-title.MARKUP&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;YEAR&lt;/code&gt; is a four-digit number, &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;MONTH&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;DAY&lt;/code&gt; are both two-digit numbers, and &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;MARKUP&lt;/code&gt; is the file extension representing the format used in the file. After that, include the necessary front matter. Take a look at the source for this post to get an idea about how it works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll also offers powerful support for code snippets:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-ruby&quot; data-lang=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;puts&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;Hi, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;#{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'Tom'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;#=&amp;gt; prints 'Hi, Tom' to STDOUT.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out the &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/docs/home&quot;&gt;Jekyll docs&lt;/a&gt; for more info on how to get the most out of Jekyll. File all bugs/feature requests at &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll&quot;&gt;Jekyll’s GitHub repo&lt;/a&gt;. If you have questions, you can ask them on &lt;a href=&quot;https://talk.jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll Talk&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">You’ll find this post in your _posts directory. Go ahead and edit it and re-build the site to see your changes. You can rebuild the site in many different ways, but the most common way is to run jekyll serve, which launches a web server and auto-regenerates your site when a file is updated.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">My Just Write a First Post Post</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blogging/2019/05/04/my-just-write-a-first-post-post.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My Just Write a First Post Post" /><published>2019-05-04T15:46:23+07:00</published><updated>2019-05-04T15:46:23+07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blogging/2019/05/04/my-just-write-a-first-post-post</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blogging/2019/05/04/my-just-write-a-first-post-post.html">&lt;p&gt;Being a programmer and generally someone who spends a great
deal of their time on the web, blogs have been an ideal source of interest 
and knowledge.  Like many others in my industry, I’ve been wanting to say I have a blog for.. alwhile.
I could go back as far as school days dabbling in HTML and CSS usually lent itself
to creating a blog site of some kind.  I would try different hosts 
beginning with Geocities, then Angelfire and find myself looking further into 
Client/Server Architecture with the inevitable Wordpress.  Initially I wanted to 
blog, but the real attraction was to delve into the
technologies.  As a result, no blog made it any further than a couple 
initial statements about my fancy new blog.  Decades later many kinds of 
newfangled ways to make your own blog has arisen to make it even easier and I still don’t have a 
blog I can present.  Here is another attempt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This time I have cleared all of my reminders and scheduled tasks to ‘Begin the blog’, 
or ‘write post on..’, and didn’t allow myself to fork my attention to 
deciding blogging frameworks, or how I could easily publish from Emacs Org Mode, 
or which languages I could build and future rewrite a blogging application in. 
Yes, this was my spare time we’re talking about, and when considering a blog
the implementation details always seemed to nudge ahead, in my time I could play around if I wanted to.
  This always lead to not having a blog of course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where to from here? A bit like going to the gym I’m just getting on with it. I’m picking up from my last
attempt using Github Pages which had been sitting idle for 5 years,
without a post that I allowed to remain. I have a mounting pile of posts to write and complete.
It has become a habit to 
take chunks of daily notes of ideas and thoughts, with the intention that some day the bits
will form a helpful passage in a blog, 
the only thing was that they didn’t budge from their scribbly note form into a blog all by themselves. 
Many of my initial posts will be picked off the pile as I see fit, touched up into 
that something that makes sense to others, and posted with a gentle sigh of relief.
This will mean a number of different type of posts being published some short, some
long, some introspective, surely some technical and hopefully helpful,
some perhaps a bit of a ramble but I’ll be happy about the process of learning
through writing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you kindly for your interest in reading thus far, hopefully you find 
it beneficial and please reach out to me if you have would like to
say something nice or to find out more.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Being a programmer and generally someone who spends a great deal of their time on the web, blogs have been an ideal source of interest and knowledge. Like many others in my industry, I’ve been wanting to say I have a blog for.. alwhile. I could go back as far as school days dabbling in HTML and CSS usually lent itself to creating a blog site of some kind. I would try different hosts beginning with Geocities, then Angelfire and find myself looking further into Client/Server Architecture with the inevitable Wordpress. Initially I wanted to blog, but the real attraction was to delve into the technologies. As a result, no blog made it any further than a couple initial statements about my fancy new blog. Decades later many kinds of newfangled ways to make your own blog has arisen to make it even easier and I still don’t have a blog I can present. Here is another attempt.</summary></entry></feed>